Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.,
الدكتور مارتن لوثر كينج الإبن،
in a 1968 speech where he reflects upon the Civil Rights Movement,
في خطاب عام 1968، حيث يتأمل حركة الحقوق المدنية،
states, "In the end,
قال: "في النهاية،
we will remember not the words of our enemies
نحن لن نتذكر كلمات أعدائنا
but the silence of our friends."
بل صمت أصدقائنا."
As a teacher, I've internalized this message.
كمدرس، استوعبت هذه الرسالة.
Every day, all around us,
كل يوم من حولنا
we see the consequences of silence
نرى آثار الصمت
manifest themselves in the form of discrimination,
تجسّد نفسها على شكل تمييز
violence, genocide and war.
وعنف وإبادة وحرب.
In the classroom, I challenge my students
في الصف، أتحدى طلابي
to explore the silences in their own lives
باستكشاف الصمت في حياتهم هم
through poetry.
من خلال الشعر.
We work together to fill those spaces,
نعمل معا بملء هذه الفراغات،
to recognize them, to name them,
للتعرف عليهم، وتسميتهم،
to understand that they don't have to be sources of shame.
وفهم أنهم لا يجب أن يكونوا مصادر للعار.
In an effort to create a culture within my classroom
في محاولة لخلق ثقافة في صفي
where students feel safe sharing the intimacies
حيث يشعر الطلاب بالأمان وهم يشاركون حميميات
of their own silences,
الصمت الخاص بهم.
I have four core principles posted on the board
لدي أربعة مبادئ جوهرية معلقة على السبورة
that sits in the front of my class,
التي في مقدمة صفي،
which every student signs at the beginning of the year:
والتي يوقع عليها كل طالب بداية العام؛
read critically, write consciously,
اقرأ ناقدًا، اكتب واعيًا،
speak clearly, tell your truth.
تحدث بوضوح، وقل حقيقتك.
And I find myself thinking a lot about that last point,
وأجد نفسي أفكر كثيرًا في تلك النقطة الأخيرة:
tell your truth.
قل حقيقتك.
And I realized that
وأدركت أنه
if I was going to ask my students to speak up,
إن كنت سأطالب طلابي بالجهر بالكلام،
I was going to have to tell my truth
فيجب عليّ إخبار حقيقتي
and be honest with them about the times
وأصدق معهم عن المرات التي
where I failed to do so.
فشلت بفعل ذلك فيها.
So I tell them that growing up,
لذا أخبرهم أنه خلال نشأتي
as a kid in a Catholic family in New Orleans,
كطفل في عائلة كاثوليكية من نيو أورلينز،
during Lent I was always taught
في الصوم الكبير كنت أُعلَّم
that the most meaningful thing one could do
أن أسمى ما قد يفعله الشخص
was to give something up,
هو التخلي عن أمر ما،
sacrifice something you typically indulge in
التضحية بشيء تشتهيه عادة
to prove to God you understand his sanctity.
لتثبت لله أنك تفهم قداسته.
I've given up soda, McDonald's, French fries,
تخليت عن المشروبات الغازية ومكدونلدز والبطاطس المقلية
French kisses, and everything in between.
والقبل الفرنسية وكل شيء بينهم.
But one year, I gave up speaking.
لكن في أحد الأعوام، تخليت عن الحديث.
I figured the most valuable thing I could sacrifice
حسبت أن أثمن ما أستطيع التضحية به
was my own voice, but it was like I hadn't realized
هو صوتي، لكن كان وكأنني لم أدرك
that I had given that up a long time ago.
أني تخليت عنه منذ زمن طويل.
I spent so much of my life
قضيت وقتًا طويلا في حياتي
telling people the things they wanted to hear
أخبر الناس ما أرادوا سمعه
instead of the things they needed to,
بدلا مما احتاجوا سمعه.
told myself I wasn't meant to be anyone's conscience
أخبرت نفسي أنني لم أعيّن كضمير للآخرين
because I still had to figure out being my own,
لأنه لا زال عليّ اكتشاف كيف أكون ضمير نفسي
so sometimes I just wouldn't say anything,
لذا في بعض الأحيان لن أقول أي شيء
appeasing ignorance with my silence,
استرضي الجهل بصمتي،
unaware that validation doesn't need words
غير مدرك أن القبول لا يحتاج لكلمات
to endorse its existence.
لإقرار وجوده.
When Christian was beat up for being gay,
حين ضرب كريستشن لكونه مثليًا،
I put my hands in my pocket
وضعت يديّ في جيبي
and walked with my head down as if I didn't even notice.
وسرت مطرقا كأني لم ألاحظ.
I couldn't use my locker for weeks because the bolt on the lock
لم أستطع استعمال خزانتي لأسابيع لأن لسان القفل
reminded me of the one I had put on my lips
ذكرني بالقفل الذي وضعته على شفتيّ
when the homeless man on the corner
حين نظر لي المشرد في الشارع
looked at me with eyes up merely searching
بعينين تبحث فقط عن تأكيد
for an affirmation that he was worth seeing.
أنه يستحق النظر إليه.
I was more concerned with touching the screen on my Apple
كنت مهتما أكثر بلمس شاشة جهازي الآبل (تفاح)
than actually feeding him one.
أكثر من إطعامه تفاحة.
When the woman at the fundraising gala
حين قالت المرأة في مهرجان التبرعات
said "I'm so proud of you.
قالت "أنا فخورة بك.
It must be so hard teaching those poor, unintelligent kids,"
من المؤكد أنه من الصعب تعليم هؤلاء الأطفال الفقراء الأغبياء،"
I bit my lip, because apparently we needed her money
عضضت شفتي، لأنه يبدو أننا احتجنا مالها
more than my students needed their dignity.
أكثر مما احتاج طلابي كرامتهم.
We spend so much time
نقضي الكثير من الوقت
listening to the things people are saying
نصغي لما يقوله الآخرون
that we rarely pay attention to the things they don't.
لدرجة أننا قلّما نركّز فيما لا يقولون.
Silence is the residue of fear.
الصمت هو من رواسب الخوف.
It is feeling your flaws
هو الشعور بعيوبك
gut-wrench guillotine your tongue.
تمزق وتمزع وتقتلع لسانك.
It is the air retreating from your chest
هو الهواء ينسحب من صدرك
because it doesn't feel safe in your lungs.
لأنه لا يشعر بالأمان في رئتيك.
Silence is Rwandan genocide. Silence is Katrina.
الصمت هو إبادة رواندا. الصمت هو كاترينا.
It is what you hear when there aren't enough body bags left.
هو ما تسمعه حين لا يبقى ما يكفي من أكياس للجثث.
It is the sound after the noose is already tied.
هو ما تسمعه بعد أن يشد الخناق.
It is charring. It is chains. It is privilege. It is pain.
إنه محرق. إنه قيود. إنه فضل. إنه ألم.
There is no time to pick your battles
لا يكفي الوقت لاختيار معاركك
when your battles have already picked you.
حين تكون معاركك قد اختارتك أصلًا.
I will not let silence wrap itself around my indecision.
لن أدع الصمت يلتف حول ترددي.
I will tell Christian that he is a lion,
سأخبر كريستشن أنه أسد،
a sanctuary of bravery and brilliance.
أنه ملاذ للشجاعة والروعة.
I will ask that homeless man what his name is
سأسأل ذاك المشرد عن اسمه،
and how his day was, because sometimes
وكيف كان يومه، لأن أحيانا
all people want to be is human.
كلما يريده الناس هو الإنسانية.
I will tell that woman that my students can talk about
سأخبر تلك المرأة أن طلابي يستطيعون التحدث
transcendentalism like their last name was Thoreau,
عن فلسفة المتعالية وكأن لقبهم ثورو،
and just because you watched one episode of "The Wire"
وأن مشاهتدكِ لحلقة من "ذا واير"
doesn't mean you know anything about my kids.
لا يعني معرفتك أي شيء عن أولادي.
So this year,
لذا هذا العام،
instead of giving something up,
بدلا من التخلي عن شيء
I will live every day as if there were a microphone
سأعيش كل يوم وكأن هناك مذياعا
tucked under my tongue,
مدسوسا تحت لساني،
a stage on the underside of my inhibition.
مسرحا في أسفل كبتي.
Because who has to have a soapbox
فمن يحتاج لمنبر
when all you've ever needed is your voice?
حين يكون كل ما تحتاجه هو صوتك؟
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)